（実渕(みぶち)）いいもの見せてあげる
I'll show you something special.
There's no way I'll let him—
（日向(ひゅうが)）
そんなもん打たせるわけ…
なっ 跳べない なんで!?
I can't jump?
Why?
（木吉(きよし)）ううっ
（根武谷(ねぶや)）おおらぁ！
Four fingers...
（火神(かがみ)）４本 止めてみせる！
I'll stop him this time!
A crossover!
（小金井(こがねい)）クロスオーバー!?
（日向）なっ…
（火神）まさか！
Could it be?
（赤司(あかし)）うっ！
What? An alley-oop?
（若松(わかまつ)）アリウープ!?
（氷室(ひむろ)）なんてバネだ
What a jump!
The Weight of Resolve
The third quarter will now begin.
（アナウンス）
これより第３クオーターを始めます
（歓声）
（日向）行くぞぉ！
Let's go, Seirin!
誠凛(せいりん)ーっ！ ファイ！
Fight!
Yeah!
（若松）おお… すげぇ気合いだ
They're really hyped up.
They're behind, but they haven't given up.
この大差で まだ諦めてねぇ
（実渕）ふっ どうかしらね
Don't be so sure.
They're just desperately
trying to shake off
むしろ必死に振り払ってる
ようにしか見えないけど
the dark despair that will
envelope them any moment now.
今にも心を
覆い尽くそうとしている—
絶望の闇を
We're counting on you, Hyuga-kun and...
（リコ）頼んだわよ 日向君
そして…
Kagami-kun.
（黒子(くろこ)）火神君
（黒子）お願いします
I'm counting on you.
Leave it to me.
（火神）おう 任せな！
（伊月(いづき)）ふっ
（根武谷）うっ
（葉山(はやま)）うわ！
（日向）えい！
スクリーン
A screen!
（伊月）えい！
Rakuzan
Seirin
He already made one!
（観客１）
開始早々 決めやがった！
Hyuga's threes!
（観客２）日向のスリー！
Defense! Let's stop this shot!
ディフェンス！ １本止めるぞ！
I'm surprised.
（岡村(おかむら)）たまげたな
この絶望的な状況でも—
Despite the desperate situation,
Seirin's spirit isn't broken.
誠凛の心はまだ
かろうじて折れておらん
バスケットに一発逆転はない
There are no quick comebacks in basketball.
But
だが 諦めない限り—
as long as they don't give up,
勝利の可能性が
ゼロパーセントになることはない
they have more than a 0% chance of winning.
Sorry,
（紫原(むらさきばら)）あのさ〜 悪いけど—
but when I said they couldn't win,
オレが〝勝てない〞って
言ったのは—
I wasn't just considering the situation.
状況を見た話だけじゃ
ないよ
What do you mean Seirin has a less
than 1% chance of winning, Aomine?
（諏佐(すさ)）誠凛に１パーセントの
可能性もないって—
どういうことだよ 青峰(あおみね)
Not yet, but soon.
（青峰）
ないじゃねぇ なくなるだ
Because Akashi's on the other team.
なぜなら赤司がいるからな
He crushes his opponents'
potential until it's all gone.
あいつは相手の可能性が—
すべてなくなるまで
摘み取っていく
えい！
Could it be?
（日向）まさか…
The outcome is 90% certain now.
（赤司）
もはや勝負は９割方決まった
But Seirin isn't completely dead yet.
だが誠凛はまだ
完全に死んではいない
Their shooter Hyuga and
ace Kagami still remain.
最後の要はシューターの日向と
エースの火神
I'll take Kagami.
よって火神は僕が
Leo, you'll take Hyuga.
日向は 玲央(れお)
Defense, black No. 4!
（審判）ディフェンス！ 黒４番
Hyuga!
日向！
Damn. That's his third.
（伊月）３つ目 ヤバイ！
It wasn't long, but I had fun, Junpei-chan.
短い間だったけど 楽しめたわよ
順平(じゅんぺい)ちゃん
He faked a Heaven shot into an Earth!
（日向）天のシュートをおとりに
地のシュート…
No, wait! I didn't hit him!
いや それより
オレは当たってない！
そんな… こんなところで！
This can't be happening now!
Not when we're so desperate!
必死に…
これからってときに なんだよ！
４番 早く手を上げて！
No. 4, raise your hands!
Seriously? I didn't hit him!
何だよ それ！
今 接触はなかった！
（リコ）ちょっ… 日向君!?
Hyuga-kun!
Raise your hands!
（審判）手を上げなさい 早く！
He lost his balance! I didn't do anything!
相手が勝手にバランスを崩したんだ
オレは悪くない！
日向！
Hyuga!
頼むよ オレは…
Please, I...
（審判）
テクニカルファウル 黒４番
Technical foul, black No. 4!
That's four. They'll have to sub him out.
（今吉(いまよし)）４つ目
もう下げるしかないな
Yikes.
（高尾(たかお)）うわっちゃ〜
We came because someone threw a tantrum
over watching the game, but...
（高尾）“最後は会場で
見届けたいのだよ”—
とか誰かさんが
だだこねるから—
感傷もそこそこに かけつけたのに
It wasn't a tantrum.
（緑間(みどりま)）こねてないのだよ
You can't be doing that, Hyuga-san.
（高尾）そりゃないっスぜ
日向さーん
（緑間）確かに
目に余る愚行だったな
It was intolerably foolish.
But I still can't blame him.
だがそれでも—
彼を責めることは
できないのだよ
That's how badly he wants to win.
それほど 勝ちたかったのだろう
What?
何か？
いや まさか真(しん)ちゃんから
そんなセリフが出るなんてな
I never thought you'd say that.
（緑間）どういうことなのだよ！
What does that mean?!
Since they beat us to reach the
finals, I was rooting for our rivals.
（笠松(かさまつ)）オレたちに勝って
ここまで来たライバルだ
誠凛びいきで見てたんだがな
But this is the end for them.
ここまでか
It's not over yet.
（黄瀬(きせ)）
いや かろうじてだけど—
They still have one last hope.
まだ最後の希望が残ってるっス
But...
けど…
It's not over yet, Seirin.
まだだよ 誠凛
I won't stop until you're completely dead.
僕が手を緩めるとしたら—
君たちが完全に
絶命したときだけだ
The door to the Zone is heartless.
ゾーンの扉は
いかなるときも無情
It never opens for those who ask for help.
すがる者に開くことは
決してない
Rakuzan
Seirin
Black, time out.
（アナウンス）
黒 タイムアウトです
The finals aren't always dramatic.
（今吉）ファイナルが必ず
ドラマチックになるとは限らん
Sometimes the favorite wins all too soon.
大本命が
あっけなく勝つのも—
またファイナルや
Their spirits are completely broken.
もはや 完全に心も折れた
Their lights of hope have been extinguished.
希望の光はすべて消えた
Seirin can't recover anymore.
誠凛は もう立ち上がれん
Do you have your answer?
（赤司）何か答えは出たかい？
まだ見つかりません
Not yet, but I won't run anymore.
でも—
ボクは もう逃げない
それだけは決めました
That much I've decided.
No.
（黒子）いやだ　勝ちたい
I want to win.
Kuroko?
黒子？
I want to win!
ボクは 勝ちたい！
無理でも 不可能でも—
Even if it's impossible, I want
us to become the best in Japan!
みんなと
日本一になりたい！
（テツヤ２号(にごう)）ワンッ
Coach, please.
（黒子）カントク お願いします
Rakuzan
Seirin
（リコ）
ゲームで大差がついたとき…
When you're this far behind,
no sport is more boring than basketball.
（リコ）バスケットほど
つまらないスポーツはない
But that's only if
（リコ）だけど それは—
ここで終わればの話！
the game ends here!
（観客１）おお 出てきたぞ！
Seirin's original trickster
is coming back out!
誠凛の元祖トリックスター！
（観客２）11番！ 黒子テツヤ！
No. 11, Kuroko Tetsuya!
（根武谷）は!?
（実渕）どういうつもり？
What?
What are they thinking?
Nothing's changed.
（葉山）何も変わってないじゃんよ
There's no point in exciting the fans.
まずギャラリーが
盛り上がっちゃダメっしょ
（黛(まゆずみ)）あげく
元祖トリックスターか
The original trickster? That's funny.
笑わせるぜ
もはや タネも仕掛けも
バレたペテン師だろ
He's an impostor whose
tricks have been revealed.
まさか まだ勝算があるつもりなら
楽観的にもほどがあるよ
Surely you're not so optimistic
that you think you can still win.
（黒子）
そんな風には考えていません
It's not like that.
I fight because I want to win. That's all.
勝ちたいから戦う　それだけです
No matter how this ends,
結果がどうだろうと—
I will not run!
ボクは逃げません！
（赤司）なるほど
無意味な決意だ
I see.
Your conviction is meaningless.
He's been nothing but selfish.
（伊月）ったく ワガママばかり
言ってくれるな
Does he have any idea how
crazy it would be if we won?
ここから勝つって
どんだけムチャか分かってんのか？
（小金井）それでも１年が
まだ上を向いているのに—
But the second-years can't lose heart
while the first-years still have hope.
オレら２年がしょぼくれてる
わけにはいかないっしょ！
We can't give up yet.
（木吉）
まだ諦めるには早すぎる！
We will win.
（火神）勝つんだ！ ただ
それだけを思って戦え！
Fight with only winning on your mind!
You can do it, guys.
（リコ）頑張って みんな！
頑張って 黒子君！
You can do it, Kuroko.
Oh, no!
（実渕）しまった！
（ホイッスル）
（誠凛部員たち）よぉし！
Yeah!
His screens are good,
（実渕）確かに彼はスクリーンの
かけ方はうまいけど—
それだけじゃないわよね
but that can't be all.
Kuroko versus Mayuzumi!
（高尾）黒子 対 黛!?
Don't act like you can stop me.
（黛）止める気マンマンの
ツラしてんじゃねぇよ
オマエに できるわけ
ねぇだろうが！
You can't possibly do that!
Mayuzumi-san, wait!
黛さん タンマ！
させっかぁ！
No, you don't!
火神！
Kagami!
Rakuzan
Seirin
わずかながら つめたか　なっ！
They closed the gap a little.
Mayuzumi versus Kuroko again?
また黛 対 黒子!?
I won't fall for it again.
（黛）同じ手に乗るかよ
Kagami's on the other side.
火神は逆サイド
I can handle anyone else who comes.
あいつ以外のヘルプなら
対応できる！
抜いた！ 木吉 ヘルプに—
He passed him! Kiyoshi's going to...
行ってない！
He's not moving!
（黛）まさか!?
Could it be?
He's letting Mayuzumi shoot?
（諏佐）黛に わざと打たせてる
Yeah. Seirin can't stop all of Rakuzan's
attacks, and they're not trying to.
そうや
誠凛は今
洛山(らくざん)の攻撃すべてに—
対応することはできんし—
するつもりもない
If they're going to shoot anyway,
they'll make their worst shooter shoot.
どうせシュートを
打たれるなら—
一番外れそうなヤツに
打ってもらう
そんなとこやろ
I see.
（黛）なるほどな
役立たずの
こいつを投入したのは—
They put this worthless player
in so I would pass him and shoot.
わざとオレに抜かせて
シュートを打たせるためってことか
ナメられたもんだ！
They underestimate me.
I'll show them what I can do!
なら こっちも—
思う存分やらせてもらうぜ！
Rakuzan's No. 5 made another basket!
（観客）
また決めたぞ！ 洛山５番！
（黛）あえて言わせてもらうぜ
旧型のシックスマン君
I'll say it again, old sixth man.
オマエじゃ オレに勝てねぇよ
You can't beat me.
おいおい 落ちる気配ねーぞ
He's not missing any shots.
作戦ミスじゃねえのか？
Did they make a mistake?
Seirin got them back!
（観客）誠凛も返した！
This reminds of something Takao-kun told me.
以前 高尾君に
言われたことを思い出します
I guess you could say I hate
you because you're like me.
（高尾）だからねー
ぶっちゃけ なんつーの？
アレ 同族嫌悪
What?
Sorry, but I still consider
myself the Phantom Sixth Man!
幻のシックスマンという
呼び名—
悪いんですが
まだ譲る気はありません！
What?
Where did he come from?
（葉山）今 どこから!?
I lost him... Impossible!
（黛）見失った バカな…
オマエ 一体 何をした!?
What did he do?
Run!
走れ！
Has his lack of presence returned?
（葉山）まさか影の薄さが戻った？
そんなバカな！
That's impossible!
But if it is, this situation...
でも そうだとしたら
このシチュエーション
Is it the Vanishing Drive?
来るのか？
バニシングドライブ！
（小金井）よし！
（伊月）よぉし ナイス！
Nice, Kagami and Kuroko!
火神 黒子！
まだまだぁ！ こっからだぜ 洛山！
We're just getting started, Rakuzan!
Has Kuroko's lack of presence returned?
黒子に影の薄さが戻ったのか？
No.
いや
（黛）
違う！ そんなことありえない
No! That's impossible!
There's nothing you can do
about your own presence!
存在感のあるなしなんて 自分で
どうこうできるもんじゃない！
（観客１）
来たぞ！ 洛山の５番 黛だ！
Here he comes! It's Rakuzan's
No. 5, Mayuzumi!
（観客２）黛の ワンオンワン！
It's a one-on-one!
（黛）はっ まさか テメェ—
Did you
上書きしたのか—
overwrite
オレに！
me?
Overwriting.
上書き 要は黛が—
He made Mayuzumi stand out more than himself.
自分より目立つように
仕向けたのだよ
That's why he kept letting Mayuzumi pass him.
黛に抜かれ続けたのも
そのためだ
A dim light is overshadowed
when a brighter light appears.
目立ち始めた光も—
より輝く光が傍らに現れれば
かすんでいく
旧型と同じ特性を持ち
旧型より高性能
Similar to the old one, but better.
That's how he dug the new model's grave.
だからこそ 掘らされた—
新型の墓穴だ
Hey!
（葉山）へいっ！
（葉山）
うわっ パス低い けど…
Low pass, but...
I'm too close!
やべっ 短っ！
（根武谷）チィッ！
Rakuzan's missing?
（森山(もりやま)）洛山が連続ミス!?
Kuroko's applying a lot
of pressure on defense.
黒子は今 ディフェンス面に
大きなプレッシャーを与えている
Since he's vanished from the court,
コート上に
さっきまでいた選手が姿を消し—
there's no telling where
the steal will come from.
いつどこからスティール
狙ってくるか—
分からないわけだからな
ただ そうやって
黒ちんが頑張っても—
But that's not enough
for Kurochin to beat Akachin.
それだけじゃ勝てないっしょ
赤ちんには
（火神）黒子
つくづくオマエはすげぇよ
Kuroko, you're amazing.
オマエが
立ち上がってなかったら—
If you hadn't stood back up,
I may have given up.
オレもあそこで
諦めてたかもしれねぇ
I won't let your ray of
hope go out this time!
だから今度こそ
消させねぇよ 絶対
オマエがつけた 希望の光を！
勝負だ　赤司！
Bring it on, Akashi!
He's entered the Zone again!
こいつ またゾーンに！
But he can't beat Sei-chan.
けど 征(せい)ちゃんには勝てないわ
前半を忘れたの？
Did he forget the first half?
（小金井）それでも
黒子の作った勢いを—
But you're the only one who can
keep Kuroko's momentum going!
つなげられるのは—
オマエだけなんだ　頼む！
Please!
（誠凛部員たち）火神！
Kagami!
He backed off?
距離を取った
Did he stop marking him? Why?
マークを外したのか？
なぜじゃ!?
（根武谷）ふざけやがって
Ridiculous!
Just shoot the three, Akashi!
さっさとスリー撃っちまえ 赤司！
（赤司）バカな
届くというのか？ そこから
Impossible.
He can reach from there?
He's even deeper in the Zone.
あの野郎
ゾーンが深くなってやがる
深く… やと？
Deeper?
He's like a wild beast.
（青峰）ゾーンのときの野性は
いよいよ獣のそれだ
How could Akashi not know what to do?
（葉山）赤司が攻めあぐねるなんて
よぉぉ！
Mayuzumi's still functioning.
黛がまだ機能している
The effects of the overwriting
aren't complete yet.
上書きは終わっていなかったんだ
Now that I know, I won't pass you.
（黛）狙いが分かれば
もう抜かねぇよ
オレが影に徹すれば—
Once I return to the shadows,
you can't overwrite me.
上書きが完成することはねぇ
（黛）パスコースがない！
There's nowhere to pass!
He thinks I won't pass him.
（黛）
こいつ オレが抜かないと踏んで
There's no one behind him.
後ろもガラ空き
つくづくウゼェ野郎だ
What an obnoxious kid.
But I won't fall for it.
だが その手にかかるかよ！
Until I find my target...
ひとまず
パスターゲットができるまで
（黛）
え？ なんでオレは抜いて…
What? Why did I pass...
（火神）うおぉ！
（黛）しまっ…
Crap!
Kurochin created a huge opening
just before he started dribbling.
今 黒ちん ドリブルの直前
わざと大きなスキを作ったよね
Yeah. It was a moment's
opening under great pressure.
ああ　プレッシャーの中
一瞬できたスキ
Mayuzumi reflexively took it
黛は反射的に
反応してしまったんじゃな
抜いちゃいかんと
分かっとったはずなのに
even though he knew he shouldn't.
要はその程度だって
ことでしょ
That's the extent of his abilities.
Returning to the shadows.
Easier said than done.
影に徹する…
言うのは簡単スけど
実はとてつもなく難しい
It takes an ironclad rationality
capable of suppressing instinct.
必要なのは 選手としての
本能を抑えこむ—
鋼のような理性
新型の幻のシックスマン
黛 千尋(ちひろ)には—
The new Phantom Sixth Man
may be more skilled,
but there's one way in which
he can't beat Kurokocchi.
性能で勝っても
黒子っちに絶対勝てないものがある
それは—
His history as the sixth man and
his will to fight for the team.
シックスマンとしての
キャリアと—
チームのために戦う意志
つまり…
In other words...
（黛）しまった！
Damn it!
今ので上書きが！
That strengthened his overwriting!
The weight of his resolve to be a shadow.
（黄瀬）影である覚悟の重さ
何!?
What?
（観客１）おお ダンク！
A dunk!
When did Kiyoshi get the ball?
（観客２）けど いつ木吉が
ボール持ったんだ？
気がついたらパスが通ってたぞ！
The pass went through before I knew it!
Rakuzan
Seirin
（伊月･小金井）よぉし！
Yes!
Kagami's stopping Akashi on defense,
ディフェンスは
火神が赤司を抑え—
オフェンスは
黒子のパスで点を取る
and they're scoring with
Kuroko's passes on offense.
まだ決して
気は抜けない状況っスけど—
They can't let their guard
down yet, but there's hope
でも 希望が出てきた
影と光の力で…
with the power of the shadow and light.
White, time out.
（アナウンス）
白 タイムアウトです
どうくるかな 洛山は
What will Rakuzan do?
とりあえず 黛は交代だろう
They'll sub out Mayuzumi.
Letting Kuroko overwrite
him was a serious mistake.
黒子の上書きを みすみす
完成させちまった罪は重い
（根武谷）くそっ！
Damn it.
Someone brought Seirin back to life.
誰かのおかげで 誠凛またなんか
息吹き返してんじゃねーか！
向こうの罠に
分かっていながらハマるのは—
Falling into a trap you can see
is nothing short of stupid.
マヌケとしか言えないわ
If the overwriting made him lose
his lack of presence, he's useless.
上書きで影の薄さは
完全に消えたなら—
パスはもう使えない　交代っしょ
Sub him out.
（黛）ったく
使えるときは好意的
They're friendly when they can use me.
使えなくなったら悪意的
When they can't, they're hostile.
つくづく
分かりやすくて助かるよ
I'm so glad they're so easy to understand.
とはいえ
反論する余地はねぇし—
But I can't argue with
them, nor do I want to.
する気もねぇよ 今さら
I'm glad to be subbed out.
喜んで交代させてもらうぜ
Akashi?
赤司…
全員少しでも
エネルギー補給しておいて！
Get your energy back, guys.
Ice and massage them.
アイシングとマッサージも！
Yes, ma'am!
（１年生たち）はいっ！
（日向）すまねぇ
これからってときに オレは…
Sorry. When we were just
getting started, I...
You worry too much, idiot.
（木吉）思いつめすぎだ ダアホ！
え？ オマエ それ…
Hey, that's—
You stole my line against Kaijo.
日向こそ 海常(かいじょう)戦で
オレのセリフとったろ　お返しだ
That's payback.
I was disappointed when you got
your technical foul, though.
まぁ 確かにテクニカルで
４つ目もらったときは正直引いたよ
I feel bad enough already.
（日向）重々 自覚してるんで—
サラッと傷口にタバスコ
ふりかけないでくれるかな
Don't rub Tabasco in the wound, Teppei-san.
鉄平(てっぺい)さん
But have faith in your friends.
けど 仲間を信じろよ 日向も
Having four fouls just makes
the situation difficult.
４ファウルで
追い詰められてることなんて—
ただのピンチだ
終わったわけじゃない
It doesn't end the game.
We'll need your threes again.
必ずまた
日向のスリーが必要になる
頼むぜ　キャプテン！
We're counting on you, Captain.
Now let's have some fun!
（小金井）
んじゃま 楽しんでこーぜ！
What? Koga, you, too?
ああっ コガにも言われたっ！
ヘヘ…
言うとなんか元気出るね これ！
Saying it really cheers you up, doesn't it?
Seriously?
え マジ？
てっきり下げてくると思ったのに
I thought they'd sub him out.
もしかして
影の薄さが切れたなら—
Can Mayuzumi use Misdirection Overflow
without his lack of presence, too?
黛もミスディレクション･
オーバーフローが使えんじゃね？
Probably not.
いや 恐らくそれはない
Huh?
That technique involves drawing
attention to yourself.
あれは自分に視線を集める技
But Mayuzumi's only trained to direct
attention away from himself.
だが黛は
自分から視線を外す—
ミスディレクション
パターンしか—
修得していないのだよ
Having Mayuzumi on the
court should hurt the team.
今の黛はデメリットのほうが
大きいはずなのに
But they still put him in.
それでも出したということは—
Did Akashi give Mayuzumi a chance
because he thinks he can still grow?
赤司は黛に まだ
成長の可能性があると信じて—
チャンスを与えた？
Akashi?
（黛）赤司
Like they said, you made a mistake.
玲央たちの言うとおり
先ほどのプレーは失態だ
下げるのが当然の選択だろう
Subbing you out would be the obvious choice.
だが オマエの力は
まだ必要だ
But we still need your strength.
We won't sub you out yet.
下げたりするものか
（赤司）洛山の勝利のために
期待しているよ
I'm counting on you to help Rakuzan win.
（火神）ボールが消えた あっ！
The ball disappeared...
Rakuzan
Seirin
Was that...
（火神）今のはまさか!?
ミスディレクション･
オーバーフロー!?
Misdirection Overflow?
No, it's a little different.
いいえ 少し違います
（黒子）黛さんは何もしてません
Mayuzumi-san didn't do anything.
黛さんは今 視線を
集めやすくなっている
He's prone to drawing attention right now.
そこに赤司君が—
Akashi-kun directed Kagami-kun's
attention to him.
火神君の視線を
誘導したんです
You think Akachin cares about
potential or motivation?
（紫原）可能性とか
やる気とか—
赤ちんが そんな
フワフワしたもん—
信じると思う？
He doesn't expect anything from him anymore.
今さら あの人に
何も期待してないよ
He's just using him
一方的に利用してるだけだね
パスを通す道具として
as a passing tool.
Preview
I'm really glad I joined the basketball team.
（小金井）オレ バスケ部に入って
本当によかった
The practices are a killer, though.
（伊月）練習は
死ぬほどキツいけどな
（小金井）なのに
みんなと一緒だと楽しくて…
But it's fun with all the guys.
We're Desperate
（伊月）勝ったら
もっと楽しいよな？
It'd be even more fun if we won!
（小金井）おう！
We'll show you what Seirin can really do!
誠凛の底力
見せてやるぜ！